# Sofyan Mahmoud

### **PROFILE**

Passionate Software Engineer with over 3 years of experience specializing in developing web applications and backend systems. Proficient in writing clear, concise code that prioritizes ease of maintenance and troubleshooting. Experienced in collaborating with both small and large teams across diverse projects and organizations. Able to work effectively in both remote and office environments as required by the company. Demonstrated enthusiasm for problem-solving, evidenced by recent achievement in the top 10% of the LeetCode community.

#### **CONTACT DETAILS**

⊠ sofyan1020@gmail.com

- . +20 11 533 832 55
- in LinkedIn
- Github
- @ Leetcode

# PERSONAL INFORMATION

Military service: **Completed** Citizenship: **Egypt** 

Family: Single without children Languages: English (B2), Arabic

(native)

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### BACK-END ENGINEER @ Settle

2023.09-pres.

- ♦ Working on a **Microservices** project to automate the process of b2b payments enabling clients to pay all their suppliers in a seamless few clicks.
- Stack: Flask/Python, Postgresql, RabbitMQ

#### C++ INSTRUCTOR @ MEC Academy

2023.08-2024.12.

- ♦ Teaching programming fundamentals, OOP, Data structure and algorithms using C++ languages
- ♦ I've taught two groups, each includes about 15 students

# BACK-END ENGINEER @ Eden technologies

2022.12-2023.09.

- ♦ Working on **Microservices** for parking system project in smart villages in **Saudi Arabia**.
- ♦ **Stack**: Java/Spring-boot, Flask/Python, Postgresql, MongoDB, RabbitMQ

FRONT-END ENGINEER @ Egyptian armed forces. **2021.11–2022.12.** 

- $\diamond$  Working on ERP system used in Egyption armed forces.
- ♦ Stack: React, Java script

FULL-STACK ENGINEER @ NajahNow

2020.06-2021.03.

- ♦ Working on **Online educational platform** used for education during COVID-19 pandemic.
- ♦ Stack: PHP/Laravel, Blade templates, JS, HTML, CSS, MySQL

# **EDUCATION**

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING. Faculty of engineering, Computer Engineering Department *Cairo University*. **2016–2021** 

- ⋄ Overall Grade: Very Good, GP grade: Excellent
- Oraduation project: A software solution called Autoeye is used to help the autonomous vehicle in adverse weather conditions, solution pipeline was dedicated in detection of the current state of the environment surrounding the vehicle and then apply computer vision and deep learning techniques to enhance the vision stream from the camera in order to be used to make the actions better

#### SKILLS

- ♦ **Concepts**: Algorithms, Data structure, Problem solving, OOP, OOD, Design patterns, RESTful APIs.
- ♦ **Tools**: Git, Github, Docker.
- ♦ **Programming Languages**: C++, Java, Python, php, Js.
- ♦ **Technologies**: Spring boot, Laravel, ReactJs, Nodejs, Flask
- ♦ **Hyper text languages**: HTML, CSS, LATEX.
- ⋄ Database: SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSql
- ♦ Queuing system: RabbitMQ
- ⋄ OS: Linux(+5 years experience), Windows

#### RECENT HUMBLE ACHIEVEMENTS

- ♦ Solve +600 problems in leetcode and reacth the top 10% in the leetcode cummunity
  2024.01
- ♦ Publish my first video in my linkedin profile explaining a string trick
   mentioned in Cracking cooding interview book

  2024.01